Where everything seems possible and nothing is what it seems.
Labyrinth is a adventure, family, fantasy film directed by Jim Henson.
Frustrated with babysitting on yet another weekend night, Sarah, a teenager with an
active imagination, summons the Goblins to take her baby stepbrother away.
When little Toby actually disappears, Sarah must follow him into a
fantastical world to rescue him from the Goblin King.
Guarding his castle is the labyrinth itself, a twisted maze of deception,
populated with outrageous characters and unknown dangers.
Jareth, played by David Bowie.
Sarah, played by Jennifer Connelly.
Toby, played by Toby Froud.
Stepmother, played by Shelley Thompson.
Father, played by Christopher Malcolm.
Hoggle / Goblin (voice), played by Brian Henson.
Labyrinth is a 1986 musical fantasy film directed by Jim Henson from a screenplay
by Terry Jones based on a story conceived by Henson and Dennis Lee.
A co-production between Henson Associates and Lucasfilm with George Lucas serving as executive producer, the film stars Jennifer Connelly as
teenager Sarah and David Bowie as Jareth, and follows Sarah's journeys through a maze to save her baby brother from the Goblin King.
Labyrinth started as a collaboration between Henson and Brian Froud
following their previous collaboration The Dark Crystal (1982).
Jones of Monty Python wrote the first draft of the film's script early
in 1984, drawing on Froud's sketches for inspiration.
The screenplay underwent several revisions by Laura Phillips, Lucas, Lee, and Elaine
May—although Jones received the film's sole screenwriting credit.
It was shot from April to September 1985 on location in Upper Nyack, Piermont, and Haverstraw,
New York, and at Elstree Studios and West Wycombe Park in the United Kingdom.
The film's fantastical creatures were designed by Froud
and created by Jim Henson's Creature Shop.
The New York Times reported that Labyrinth had a budget of $25 million.
The film underperformed at the United States box office,
grossing $12.9 million during its US theatrical run.
However, it was a success in the United Kingdom and
overseas, grossing over $34 million worldwide.
Labyrinth was first met with a mixed critical response upon its release, which contributed
to a difficult period of Henson's career, according to his son Brian Henson.
It was the last feature film that Henson directed, and over the
years it has been re-evaluated by many critics.
A success on home video and television broadcasts,
Labyrinth has gained a large cult following.
The film has been adapted into a variety of media, including
books, video games, board games and comics.
Tokyopop published a four-volume comic sequel Return to Labyrinth between 2006 and 2010, and Archaia
Entertainment published a comic prequel Labyrinth: Coronation between 2018 and 2019.
In January 2016, it was announced that a sequel was in development.
The film explores themes of rescue, race against time, maze, castle, musical.
The tone is mind_bending.